Subhash Khanna

Consulting Actuary



ABOUT ME

Consulting Actuary with more than eleven years of experience on a wide range of large scale actuarial, risk management and data analytics projects. Besides actuaria technical skills, key skills include:

- Leadership and team management
- Effective project management
- Excellent verbal and written communication
- Programming skills (VBA; Python Power BI; SQL; Web development)



6 +91 9971 9868 23

www.subhash-khanna.in

Experience

Consulting Actuary

Milliman India Pvt. Ltd

since Jan 2015

One of the founding members of Milliman's life insurance consulting practice based in New Delhi. We started as a five-member team which has now grown to 60+ members. A qualified actuary with work experience in various projects, including IPO preparation work for clients in India, data and cash flow modelling, statuary valuations, risk-based capital calculations, risk management, pricing & product design, and M&As. I am currently responsible for:

- Leading statutory valuation team for a large life insurer;
- Consulting projects in Asia and the Middle East; and
- Marketing and business development.

Asst. Vice President Swiss Re, Bangalore

Sept 2012 - June 2014

Heavily involved with the development of a unified global actuarial model (a single model to produce results across multiple reporting regimes/geographies). Successfully supported the implementation of an enterprise-wide actuarial system to automate financial reporting. The modelling best practices learnt from this role have proven to be of immense value to all projects.

Actuarial Consultant SunGard, Hong Kong

Feb 2010 - Sept 2012

As part of FIS's (formerly known as SunGard) actuarial consulting team in Hong Kong, responsible for the review and implementation of actuarial models for life insurance companies in Asia. Responsibilities also included pre-sales activities and marketing of the Prophet system.

Preferred consultant for client training on Prophet, Prophet ALS and Prophet Enterprise.

Business Analyst – Marketing Hewlett-Packard, Bangalore

May 2008 - Feb 2010

Responsible for the analysis of web marketing campaigns using statistical modelling and algorithms to study campaign effectiveness. Developed several tools for web analytics using programming skills which helped focus on deriving valuable insights on marketing campaigns effectiveness run by Hewlett-Packard globally.

Education and skills

Fellow

Institute of Actuaries of India
Institute and Faculty of Actuaries, UK

2020 2018

M.Sc. Applied Operational Risk (University Medalist)
B.Sc. (Hons.) Statistics (University Medalist)

University of Delhi

2006 - 2008









